<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project on Mélanie Brégou</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project on Mélanie Brégou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Surgical Tool Detection with YOLOv8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dl/yolov8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dl/yolov8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of this project made with Pauline Spinga was to try to detect surgical tools on images and then on video streams.
We used a Kaggle dataset with different approachs to achieve a better classification and detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dataset&#34;&gt;Dataset&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to find a dataset. We found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/dilavado/labeled-surgical-tools/data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; a dataset of 2000 images divided into 4 classes :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scalpel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clamp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Straight Scissors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curved Scissors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dataset also contains images in which we can see pairs of tools or all 4 in the same image. We notice that most of the images are similar, even if tools are different. The background is either gray or black. Thus, one pitfall is that background and objects can be easily confused.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving robust segmentation of lung regions in CT images irrespective to pathology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dl/lung-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dl/lung-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this research project, I collaborated with Clarisse Nouet and Clara Stavun under the supervision of Catalin Fetita, Noureddine Khiati and Antoine Didier from ARTEMIS departement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;context-and-problem-statement&#34;&gt;Context and Problem Statement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;infiltrative-lung-pathologies&#34;&gt;Infiltrative Lung Pathologies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infiltrative lung diseases manifest as a progressive disintegration of lung tissues, resulting in impaired functioning. They can obstruct up to 40%, as depicted in the following images, representing lungs affected by IIP (fibrosis), Covid-19, and ARDS (consolidations).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
