<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Human Computer Interface on Mélanie's Blog</title><link>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/hci/</link><description>Recent content in Human Computer Interface on Mélanie's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/hci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a Portfolio Website with Hugo and Deploying on GitHub Pages</title><link>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/hci/blog-creation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/hci/blog-creation/</guid><description>As part of my Human-Computer Interface class, I was tasked with creating a blog to showcase my work during my master&amp;rsquo;s program. I opted to build my website using Hugo, a fast and modern static site generator. In this guide, I will walk you through the steps to set up your own portfolio website using Hugo and deploy it on GitHub Pages.
Here are the different steps to set up this portfolio :</description></item><item><title>Affordance in daily life</title><link>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/hci/affordance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/hci/affordance/</guid><description>Introduction After a 6-hour lecture introducing Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), our first homework was to find real-life objects that exemplify the concept of affordances in HCI.
Affordances Definition Before we delve into real-life examples, let&amp;rsquo;s define what an affordance is in the context of HCI. Affordance refers to the inherent usability or functionality of an object, interface, or system. It&amp;rsquo;s a concept that suggests what actions can be performed with an object and how those actions can be intuitively understood by users.</description></item></channel></rss>