<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ar on Mélanie Brégou</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/ar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ar on Mélanie Brégou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/ar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Snow sleigh game on Hololens2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ar-vr/sleigh-ar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ar-vr/sleigh-ar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introducing our AR game circuit developed using Unity3D and MRTK3 for HoloLens 2. This project was brought to life through a collaborative effort between myself and Pauline Spinga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the key steps of the project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In designing the circuit within a ski station environment, we sourced various models from free3D, turbosquid, and sketchfab websites. Additionally, we crafted a custom panel featuring our school logo. All elements were assembled in Blender, with additional snow textures for ambiance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tap to Place App</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ar-vr/tap-to-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ar-vr/tap-to-place/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the context of our AR course at Institut Polytechnique de Paris, we were asked to develop a mobile application with AR Foundation in Unity to place object on the ground by taping its desired place on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; controls&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;tap-to-place.mov&#34; type=&#34;video/quicktime&#34;&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the different steps of the project :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;unity-settings&#34;&gt;Unity settings&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to make the application work on my Iphone I tried several Unity versions but the one which worked was the 2022.3.10f1.
Then create a new project with AR Mobile Core template&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
