<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mélanie Brégou</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mélanie Brégou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Ubiquitous Computing: A Vision and Reality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/ubiquitous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/ubiquitous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1991, computer scientist Mark Weiser introduced the concept of &amp;ldquo;ubiquitous computing,&amp;rdquo; envisioning a world where technology seamlessly integrates into our daily lives. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore whether we are already living in a world of ubiquitous computing, highlighting both what has been achieved and what remains on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-is-ubiquitous-computing-&#34;&gt;What is &amp;ldquo;Ubiquitous Computing&amp;rdquo; ?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubiquitous computing, often referred to as &amp;ldquo;pervasive computing,&amp;rdquo; is a paradigm where computing technology is seamlessly embedded in the environment, making it an invisible and integral part of our daily lives. It envisions a world where computers are so interwoven into our surroundings that they operate unnoticed but provide significant benefits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The shape of smartphones</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/current/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/current/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mobile phones have come a long way in terms of design over the past decade. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a closer look at the evolution of mobile phone design and shape, with a specific focus on weight, thickness, and display size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;weight-matters&#34;&gt;Weight Matters:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile phone manufacturers have been on a mission to make our devices smaller and lighter. While the average weight of mobile phones has remained relatively consistent, it&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that modern high-end smartphones now pack more features into smaller, lighter packages. However, the quest for feature-rich phones has driven the trend towards slightly heavier devices. The finish of a phone, such as metal or tempered glass, can add to its weight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing human habilities in the age of Augmented Reality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/futur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/futur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced world, technology has become an integral part of our daily lives, and it&amp;rsquo;s continually reshaping the way we go about our routines. Augmented Reality (AR) is one such technology that holds the potential to enhance human abilities and make our lives more efficient and enjoyable. In this blog article, I present an innovative project aimed at transforming the way we plan meals, manage kitchen inventory, and shop for groceries – all through the lens of AR.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Input Devices and Interaction Paradigms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/failed_input/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/failed_input/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rKwKWXOPFbs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FeetThrough: Electrotactile Foot Interface&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; is an interesting haptic input device that falls into the category of a sensory or haptic user interface. It aims to provide haptic feedback to the user&amp;rsquo;s feet, enhancing their sensory experience during foot-based activities, such as walking, stepping on virtual textures, or interacting with virtual environments. While it&amp;rsquo;s a promising concept with potential benefits, there are factors that have contributed to its limited success or challenges it may face in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Display</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/ultimate_display/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/ultimate_display/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will delve into the visionary concepts put forth by Ivan Sutherland in his seminal paper, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://worrydream.com/refs/Sutherland%20-%20The%20Ultimate%20Display.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Ultimate Display&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; written in 1965. He envisaged several possibilities, some of which have already materialized, while others remain on the horizon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;advanced-graphics-and-visualization&#34;&gt;Advanced Graphics and Visualization:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sutherland anticipated the development of computer displays capable of rendering plot, curves or graphics. Today, modern graphics cards and software can produce highly detailed and realistic 2D and 3D graphics for applications such as gaming and scientific simulations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation of HCI researcher</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/researcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/researcher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;exploring-the-pioneering-hci-research-of-dr-elizabeth-churchill&#34;&gt;Exploring the Pioneering HCI Research of Dr. Elizabeth Churchill&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;brief-introduction&#34;&gt;Brief introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://elizabethchurchill.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Elizabeth Churchill&lt;/a&gt;, currently a Director of User Experience at Google in Mountain View, California, has drawn on social, computer, engineering and data sciences to create innovative end-user applications and services for the past 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;academic-background&#34;&gt;Academic Background&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She holds a PhD from the University of Cambridge, an honorary Doctor of Science (DSc.) from the University of Sussex, and in September will be awarded an honorary doctorate from the University of Stockholm. In 2016 she received a Citris-Banatao Institute Award Athena Award for Women in Technology for her Executive Leadership.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affordance in daily life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/affordance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/affordance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a 6-hour lecture introducing Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), our first homework was to find real-life objects that exemplify the concepts in HCI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;affordances&#34;&gt;Affordances&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;definition&#34;&gt;Definition&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we delve into real-life examples, let&amp;rsquo;s define what an affordance in HCI. Affordance refers to the inherent &lt;strong&gt;usability or functionality of an object, interface, or system&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a concept that suggests what actions can be performed with an object and how those actions can be intuitively understood by users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing a Rollerball Game in Unity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/simple-unity-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/simple-unity-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I will walk you through the process of developing a rollerball game in Unity, where the player controls a ball on a plane, collecting stars while avoiding red enemies. My game includes both static and shooter enemies, a health system with three lives, and a Game Over screen that allows players to restart or exit the game. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the development process step by step.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Installation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/unity-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/unity-install/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I installed Unity on Mac M1 sucessfully and in this article I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a brief step-by-step guide on how to install Unity based on Léa Saunier&amp;rsquo;s tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;step-1-download-unity-hub&#34;&gt;Step 1: Download Unity Hub&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin by downloading Unity Hub from &lt;a href=&#34;https://unity.com/download&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://unity.com/download&lt;/a&gt;. Unity Hub acts as a central management tool for your Unity projects and installations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;step-2-connect-your-accountlicense&#34;&gt;Step 2: Connect Your Account/License&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Unity Hub and log in with your Unity account or license to access Unity&amp;rsquo;s features and manage your licenses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Portfolio Website with Hugo and Deploying on GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/blog-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hci/blog-creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my Human-Computer Interface class, I was tasked with creating a blog to showcase my work during my master&amp;rsquo;s program. I opted to build my website using Hugo, a fast and modern static site generator. In this guide, I will walk you through the steps to set up your own portfolio website using Hugo and deploy it on GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the different steps to set up this portfolio :&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
