<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Unity on Mélanie Brégou</title><link>https://melaniebrg.github.io/categories/unity/</link><description>Recent content in Unity on Mélanie Brégou</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melaniebrg.github.io/categories/unity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Escape Game in VR</title><link>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/ar-vr/escape-vr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/ar-vr/escape-vr/</guid><description>Discover our virtual reality (VR) escape game, crafted by Mélanie Brégou and Pauline Spinga. Inspired by fantastic universes and Unity Store&amp;rsquo;s Escape Room assets, we have developed original enigmas: from recreating melodies to assembling puzzles, all to unravel clues for escaping our magical-themed house.
Set Up To begin our VR game development journey, we meticulously set up our project environment in Unity. Here&amp;rsquo;s a step-by-step guide on how we initiated the project:</description></item><item><title>Snow sleigh game on Hololens2</title><link>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/ar-vr/sleigh-ar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/ar-vr/sleigh-ar/</guid><description>Introducing our AR game circuit developed using Unity3D and MRTK3 for HoloLens 2. This project was brought to life through a collaborative effort between myself and Pauline Spinga.
Here are the key steps of the project:
Design In designing the circuit within a ski station environment, we sourced various models from free3D, turbosquid, and sketchfab websites. Additionally, we crafted a custom panel featuring our school logo. All elements were assembled in Blender, with additional snow textures for ambiance.</description></item><item><title>Tap to Place App</title><link>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/ar-vr/tap-to-place/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/ar-vr/tap-to-place/</guid><description>In the context of our AR course at Institut Polytechnique de Paris, we were asked to develop a mobile application with AR Foundation in Unity to place object on the ground by taping its desired place on the screen.
Your browser does not support the video tag. Here are the different steps of the project :
Unity settings In order to make the application work on my Iphone I tried several Unity versions but the one which worked was the 2022.</description></item><item><title>3D platform game Unity</title><link>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/cg/unity-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/cg/unity-project/</guid><description>Introduction After a 12-hour class at the Institut Polytechnique de Paris, where we explored the fundamentals of Unity, Pauline Spinga and I embarked on a creative project to model and develop a music-themed platform game named &amp;ldquo;Virtuoso&amp;rdquo;. In this game, players step into the shoes of Vivaldi, a character who has lost his piano and guitar and must embark on a journey through the changing seasons to recover his instruments while collecting musical notes along the way.</description></item><item><title>Illustrations on image encryption and steganography Lab</title><link>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/dcp/encryption-lab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/dcp/encryption-lab/</guid><description>Name Course Date Mélanie Brégou Digital content protection 06/10/2023 Objective : delve into image encryption and steganography, exploring classical ciphers and digital techniques.
Table of Contents CAESAR cipher Simple substitution cipher Simple transposition cipher LSB (lowest significant bit) steganography Image compression in JPG Image compression in PNG LSB with 2 significant bit from matplotlib import image import matplotlib.pyplot as plt import numpy as np import random from PIL import Image Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s display the images used for this lab.</description></item></channel></rss>