<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>unity on Mélanie Brégou</title><link>https://melaniebrg.github.io/categories/unity/</link><description>Recent content in unity on Mélanie Brégou</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://melaniebrg.github.io/categories/unity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3D platform game Unity</title><link>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/cg/unity-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/cg/unity-project/</guid><description>Introduction After a 12-hour class at the Institut Polytechnique de Paris, where we explored the fundamentals of Unity, Pauline Spinga and I embarked on a creative project to model and develop a music-themed platform game named &amp;ldquo;Virtuoso&amp;rdquo;. In this game, players step into the shoes of Vivaldi, a character who has lost his piano and guitar and must embark on a journey through the changing seasons to recover his instruments while collecting musical notes along the way.</description></item><item><title>Illustrations on image encryption and steganography Lab</title><link>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/dcp/encryption-lab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://melaniebrg.github.io/posts/dcp/encryption-lab/</guid><description>Name Course Date Mélanie Brégou Digital content protection 06/10/2023 Objective : delve into image encryption and steganography, exploring classical ciphers and digital techniques.
Table of Contents CAESAR cipher Simple substitution cipher Simple transposition cipher LSB (lowest significant bit) steganography Image compression in JPG Image compression in PNG LSB with 2 significant bit from matplotlib import image import matplotlib.pyplot as plt import numpy as np import random from PIL import Image Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s display the images used for this lab.</description></item></channel></rss>